Guide to the International Monitor Institute Records, 1986-2006 and undated RL.00604
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Organizational Records Series, 1986-2006, 43 boxes
  - Middle East Archives Subseries, 1989-2001 and undated
    This subseries contains material regarding human rights abuses in the Middle East, focusing primarily on Iran, Iraq, Jordon, Kuwait and their Kurdish populations. Material formats include overviews of the Middle East Archive, trip itineraries, interviews with political figures, news articles, and correspondence. The majority of correspondence deals with news and film distribution outlets, witness documentaries and collections of other visual material from both European and Gulf networks. Legal documents primarily include license agreements with organizations such as Amnesty International. Tape logs and synopses, tape annotations, and lists of tapes to purchase also comprise this subseries. Additional correspondence can be found under the subsection "People." Further audiovisual material on the Middle East can be found in the International Monitor Institute Middle East Archive records, also at the Rubenstein Library.
    - Middle-East Archive (Box OR26)
      - Afghan refugee women and children, 1989-1991 (Box OR26)
      - Al-Jamali interview tape, 2000 Dec. 6 (Box OR26)
      - Al-Khoei Foundation, 1998 and 1999 (Box OR26)
      - Al-Queda, 2002 (Box OR26)
      - "Al-Queda and the Question of State Sponsorship" by Alan F. Fogelquist, Ph.D., International Monitor Institute, completed 2002 Aug. 29 (Box OR26)
        Includes CD-ROM an diskette
      - Amendment to Federal Assistance Award, 2001 Apr. 30 (Box OR26)
      - American Airlines, Seth Jameson correspondence, 2002 Jul. 29 (Box OR26)
      - American Kurdish Information Network (AKIN) Kurdish News, 2000 Sep. (Box OR26)
      - Arab film distribution, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - Arab leaders meet in Jordon - Newsweek article, 2001 Apr. 2 (Box OR26)
      - Arab Organization for Human Rights (AOHR), 19999 (Box OR26)
      - Articles - Afghanistan and Taliban, undated (Box OR26)
      - Article on Gwynne Roberts - Saddam's bombs, 2001 (Box OR26)
      - Articles - Iraq, 1998-2000 (Box OR26)
      - Articles - Sarah Graham Brown on Kurds, 1999 (Box OR26)
      - Association of Moving Image Archivists (AMIA)-L correspondence regarding DVD format, 1999 May (Box OR26)
      - AMIA Eight Annual Conference, 1998 Dec. 7-12 (Box OR26)
      - British staff to contact - Britain trip, 2000 and undated (Box OR26)
      - CBC News - Canada contact list, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - CBC - witness documentaries, 1993-2000 (Box OR26)
      - Collection of visual materials - Iraq, 2001-2002 (Box OR26)
      - Constitutional Monarchy Movement - Iraq, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - Contacts - general, 1999 and undated (Box OR26)
      - Contacts - Mid-East, 1999 Oct. 20 (Box OR26)
      - Contact notes, etc., undated (Box OR26)
      - Correspondence to Karim Ghezraoui, 1999 Aug. 31 (Box OR26)
      - "The Crisis in Iraq: Two Essays," John Tirman, undated (Box OR26)
      - Department of State briefing index, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - DHL commercial invoice, 2001 Jul. 10 (Box OR26)
      - Earth imaging - Iraq, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - Europe archives trip, 2001 Jul. (Box OR26)
      - European Network - contacts, undated (Box OR26)
      - European TV, 2000 (Box OR26)
      - Faylee Kurds Community Trust, 2000 Apr. 10 (Box OR26)
      - Frontline - survival of Saddam, 2000 and undated (Box OR26)
      - Frontline tapes, 2000 Jul. 24 (Box OR26)
      - Gulf/2000, 1997-2000 (Box OR26)
      - Gulf conference notes, 2000 May 2-3 (Box OR26)
      - Gulf War - reading statistics, undated (Box OR26)
      - Halabja - seminars, 1998 Nov. (Box OR26)
      - "Halabja: Ten Years Later," 60 Minutes transcript, 1998 Mar. 1 (Box OR26)
      - Hambastegi 85, International Federation of Iraqi Refugees, 1999 (Box OR26)
      - HRA video - tape logs, script, undated (Box OR26)
      - Human rights seminar, London, 2000 Jan. (Box OR26)
      - Human Rights Watch abbreviated tapes synopses, undated (Box OR26)
      - Human Rights Watch California Committee Report, 2000 spring (Box OR26)
      - Human Rights Watch on embargo and war crimes tribunal, 1998-2000 (Box OR26)
      - Human Rights Watch, Tape 9 synopsis - three interviews in Goptapa and Suliemaniyah, undated (Box OR26)
      - Human Rights Watch - tapes, 1996 Sep. (Box OR26)
      - Hussein documentary, 1999-2000 (Box OR26)
      - Inside the Kill Box: Fighting the Gulf War, 2001 (Box OR26)
      - Institut National d'Audiovisuel, 2000 (Box OR27)
      - International Action Center, "Challenge to Genocide" video, 1999-2000 (Box OR27)
      - International Campaign to Indict Iraqi War Criminals (INDICT), 1999 Oct. 24 (Box OR27)
      - "Iran and the Surrounding World since 1500," conference, UCLA 2000 Apr. 14-15 (Box OR27)
      - Iran - DHL Worldwide Express, 1999 (Box OR27)
      - Iran - "Human Rights Violations in Iran" conference, 2000 May (Box OR27)
      - Iran notes, undated (Box OR27)
      - Iran Press Service, 1998 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq, 1994-1997 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq charities in United Kingdom, 2000 Aug. 15 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq contacts - London, etc., 2000 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq Democratic Movement in Britain, undated (Box OR27)
      - Iraq footage collections, undated (Box OR27)
      - Iraq Foundation, 1997-1999 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq overviews and IMI involvement, 2001 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Iraq Research and Documentation Project, 1999 Nov. 16 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq retreat ideas, 2000 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq sanctions information, 1998 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Iraq searches for special reports and periodic broadcasts, 1999 (Box OR27)
      - Iraq National Congress (INC), 2000 Jan. 12 (Box OR27)
      - Islamic Republic of Iran Broadcasting (IRIB) contacts, 2000 Aug. (Box OR27)
      - Israel Film Archive, 1999-2000 (Box OR27)
      - "Jim F." meeting notes, undated (Box OR27)
      - Jordon, 2000 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Jordan Times contacts, 2000 (Box OR27)
      - Journeyman Pictures notes, 1991-2000 (Box OR27)
      - Jordanian contacts, 2000 (Box OR27)
      - Kurdish conference notes, Washington D.C., 2000 Apr. 17-18 (Box OR27)
      - Kurdish Human Rights Project (Kerim Yildiz, director), 1999-2000 (Box OR27)
      - Kurish interviews, 1992 and 1996 (Box OR27)
      - Kurdistan trip, 1998 Sep. (Box OR27)
      - Kuwait Information Office, Washington D.C., 2000 (Box OR27)
      - Kuwait and Jordan trip, 2001 Jan. (Box OR27)
      - Kuwait TV - Ministry of Information, 2000 Jan. 12 (Box OR27)
      - March/April trip, 2001 (Box OR27)
      - The Middle East Archive multimedia database - CD index and archive titles (Iraqi Kurdistan), 2002 (Box OR27)
      - Middle East - untitled overview, undated (Box OR27)
      - Miscellaneous, 2000 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Miscellaneous abbreviated tap synopses, 1999-2000 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Miscellaneious correspondents, 1998 and undated (Box OR27)
      - Narrative report - Iraq, 2001 Jan.-Mar. (Box OR28)
      - National Archives, 2000 (Box OR28)
      - National Film Board of Canada, 2000 and undated (Box OR28)
      - The National Security Archive, undated (Box OR28)
      - News Hour shows on sanctions - transcripts, 2000 (Box OR28)
      - Newsline, Kurdish Human Rights Project (KHRP), 2000 winter, spring/early summer (Box OR28)
      - News World 99 speakers and delegates (potential contacts), 1999 Feb. 11 (Box OR28)
      - Norway TV, 2000 (Box OR28)
      - Notes - various, 2000-2002 and undated (Box OR28)
      - Paris Kurdish Institute, 2001 Sep. (Box OR28)
      - Paris Kurdish Institute film notes, 2000 and undated (Box OR28)
      - Patriotic Union of Kurdistan (D.C.), 1998 Aug. 31 (Box OR28)
      - Peace Center of Iran - correspondence, 2000 (Box OR28)
      - People
        - al-Bayati, Hamid, The Supreme Council for Islamic Revolution in Iraq (SCIRI), 2000 (Box OR28)
        - al-Haidari, Thaer, fax in Arabic, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Al-Hakim, Sahib, Organization of Human Rights in Iraq, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Al-Rubaie, Mowaffak, 1999-2000 (Box OR28)
        - Alwishah, Ahmed, Iraq Project, undated (Box OR28)
        - Aimin, Bakhtian, undated (Box OR28)
        - Amitay, Mike, Washington Kurdish Institute, 1998 (Box OR28)
        - Barker, Greg, film finding, undated (Box OR28)
        - Bassiouni, Cherif at International Campaign to Indict Iraqi War Criminals (INDICT), 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Bhat, Amin - Kashmir letter, 1998 (Box OR28)
        - Chalabi, Ahmed, 1999 Oct. 24 (Box OR28)
        - Ramsey, Clark, undated (Box OR28)
        - Clwyd, Ann, INDICT, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - el-Batal, Kamal, Human Rights in Lebanon, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Eshaiker, Muhannad, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Feinstein, Diane, United States senator, 1998 Aug. 28 (Box OR28)
        - Feldman, Marla, Gulf War document producer, 2000 Oct. 26 (Box OR28)
        - Galbraith, Peter, undated (Box OR28)
        - Ghabra,Shafeeq, Kuwait Information Office, 2000 (Box OR28)
        - Gragg, Theo letter, undated (Box OR28)
        - Haidar, Ary, Kurdish Service, 1998 (Box OR28)
        - Hiltermann, Joost, 1997 (Box OR28)
        - Jameson, Seth, 1998-2001 (Box OR28)
        - Jawad, Ghanim, Al-Khoei, 1999-2000 (Box OR28)
        - Kamali, Arash, Washington Kurdish Institute and Meridian International Center, 1998 (Box OR28)
        - Kassem, Sadool filmaker - Iraq, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - King, Jennifer, 1999-2000, undated (Box OR28)
        - Kraham, Sherri, 2000 (Box OR28)
        - Makiya, Kanan, The Iraq Research and Documentation Project (IRDP), including Gazette article, 2000 Apr. 20 (Box OR28)
        - Mansouri, Moslem, film director, 1996-1999 (Box OR28)
        - McKiernan, Kevin, 1999-2000 (Box OR28)
        - Nosrat, Hossein, 2000 (Box OR28)
        - Packer, John, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Qazwihi, Mustapha, 1999 and undated (Box OR28)
        - Rashid, Latif, 1999-2000 (Box OR28)
        - Rejali, Darius, 1998 (Box OR28)
        - Ricciardone, Frank, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Roberts, Gwynne, 2000 (Box OR28)
        - Soler, Joel, "Uncle Saddam," undated (Box OR28)
        - van der Stoel, Max, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Xulam, Kani, American Kurdish Information Network (AKIN) 1996-2000 and undated (Box OR28)
        - Zahedi, Alireza, The Peace Center of Iran, 1999 (Box OR28)
        - Zebari, Hoshyar, Kurdistan Demcoratic Party (KDP), 2000 (Box OR28)
        - Ziaifar, 1999 (Box OR28)
      - Photos of Iraqi officials, undated (Box OR28)
      - Research missions - Iraq, Kuwait, Iran, 1991-1992 (Box OR29)
      - The Revolutionary Association of the Women of Afghanistan (RAWA), undated (Box OR29)
      - Roberts, Gwynne - shot lists, Kurdistan/BBC Everyman, undated (Box OR29)
      - Roberts, Gwynne - Kurd tapes list, 2000 (Box OR29)
      - Saddam Hussein: War Crimes and Crimes Against the Iraqi People, conference, undated (Box OR29)
      - Satellite contacts, 2000 Jul. (Box OR29)
      - Scheffer, David - war crimes list, undated (Box OR29)
      - Sons of Saddam - Maxim story, 2001 (Box OR29)
      - Staff meetings notes, 2000 Dec. (Box OR29)
      - The Supreme Council for Islamic Revolution in Iraq (SCIRI) - Iraqi update, 2000 (Box OR29)
      - Tape list and annotations regarding Iraq and Middle East, 2000 (Box OR29)
      - Tape notes, undated (Box OR29)
      - Transcripts of CNN Impact - United Nations-Iraq, 1998 Mar. 1 (Box OR29)
      - Tapes to purchase, 1999 (Box OR29)
      - "United Nations Security Council Must Ease Iraq Crisis," 2000 Mar. 24 (Box OR29)
      - United Nations, Television and Video and United Nations Radio, 1997-1998 (Box OR29)
      - United Nations Relief and Works Agency (UNRWA) - Palestine refugees, 1997-1999 and undated (Box OR29)
      - Video Cario, 2000 (Box OR29)
      - War crimes tribunals, undated (Box OR29)
      - Washington D.C. - trip, Saddam Hussein conference, 2000 Sep. (Box OR29)
      - Washington D.C. visitor's information, undated (Box OR29)
      - Witness video archive, 2000 (Box OR29)
      - World News Connection (WNC) - for research, 1999-2000 (Box OR29)
      - WNC -Saddam Hussein, 1999-2000 (Box OR29)
      - World Images/Amnesty International License Agreement, 2000 Apr. (Box OR29)
      - Zagros, 1999 Apr. (Box OR29)
  - Rwanda Archive Subseries, 1993-2001 and undated
    This subseries consists almost entirely of transcripts of the Radio-Télévision Libres des Milles Collines broadcasts inciting genocide, featuring prominently journalists Gaspard Gahie, Valerie Bemeriki, Kantano Kabimana, Anani Nkurunziza, and Georges Ruggiu. Other materials include Rwanda Tribunal commendation letters, interviews with victims and perpetrators, United Nations Security Council resolutions, archive database information, information on documentaries of the genocide, and scholarly material on radio as an instrument of genocide. Further correspondence can be found under the subsection "People." Further audiovisual material on Rwanda can be found in the International Monitor Institute Rwanda Archive records, also at the Rubenstein Library.
    - ABC News London - "The Killing Fields of Rwanda," 1994 (Box OR30)
    - Appendices, 1993-1996 (Box OR30)
    - Articles, general, 1999 (Box OR30)
    - Brief sample of e-mail correspondence between Kaiser Rizvi, the supervising technician at Rwandan Tribunal in Kagli, and the IMI's Rwandan Archives in Los Angeles, 1998 Jul. 30-Sep. 4 (Box OR30)
    - Du Groupe Ad Hoc Rwanda A La Commission Des Affaires Etrangeres, 1997 Jan. 7 (Box OR30)
    - International Criminal Tribunal Rwanda, 1998-1999 (Box OR30)
    - International Criminal Tribunal Rwanda database correspondence, 1998 (Box OR30)
    - International Criminal Tribunal Rwanda updates, 1998-1999 (Box OR30)
    - Lawyers Committee for Human Rights, Rwanda, 1997 Jul. (Box OR30)
    - People
      - Austin, Kathi, Arms and Conflict Program at the Fund for Peace, Director, 1994-2000 and undated (Box OR30)
      - Austin, Kathi - notes and paperwork on Rwanda tapes, 1996 and undated (Box OR30)
      - Fisk, Mary, 1996-1997 (Box OR30)
      - Jones, Rachel, National Correspondent, Washington Bureau, 1996-1997 and undated (Box OR30)
      - Muna, Bernard, International Criminal Tribunal Rwanda (ICTR) Deputy Prosecutor, 1999 Mar. (Box OR30)
      - Mushiga, Richard - Rwanda database, 1997 (Box OR30)
      - Rudasingwa, Ambassador, 1997 Nov. 21 (Box OR30)
    - Radio as an instrument for genocide, 2001 (Box OR30)
    - The Rwanda Archive radio broadcast transcripts
      - 002/RTLM 2: Journalists Kantano Habimana, Georges Ruggiu, et al. 1994 May 16 (Box OR30)
      - 004/RTLM 4: Journalists Gaspard Gahige, Valerie Bemeriki, Kantano Habimana, Georges Ruggiu, Jean Bamwanga, regarding call against Tusis, 1994 Apr. 12 (Box OR30)
      - 014/RTLM 13: Gaspard Gahige, Kantano Habimana, Ananie Nkurunziza, 1994 May 29 (Box OR30)
      - 037B/RTLM 52: Journalists Gaspard Gahige, Valerie Bemeriki, Ananie Nkurunziza regarding international intervention, 1994 June 22 (Box OR31)
      - 045/RTLM: Jouranlist Kantano Habimana regarding Rwandan Patriotic Front (RPF), 1994 Jan. 6 (Box OR31)
      - 049A/Mesindik (Sindikubwabo at Butare): Journalists Rwakana Gaspard, Hyacinthe Bicamumpaka, Cyprian Musabirema, undated (Box OR31)
      - 052/Interahamwe: Major Mutambuka, undated (Box OR31)
      - 053/Loose tape Mugesera Leon MRND: political speech regarding invasion of Rwanda, 1992 Nov. 22 (Box OR31)
      - 062A/RTLM A 1908: unidentified journalist regarding security measures, 1994 Apr. 11 (Box OR31)
      - 062B/RTLM B 1908: unidentified journalist, 1994 Apr. 11 (Box OR31)
      - 065A/Cassette A 1911: Journalists Kantano Kabimana, Jean Baptiste Bamwanga et al., 1994 Apr. 14 (Box OR31)
      - 065B/Cassette A 1911: Journalists Hyacinthe Bicamumpaka and Jean Francois Nsengiyumva, interview with Prime Minister John Kambanda, Colonel Renzaho addresses people of Kigali, summary of President Sindikubwabo's message, 1994 Apr. 14 (Box OR31)
        Continued from 065A.
      - 070/A1916: Journalist Gaspard Gahige regarding Inkotanyi threats, 1994 Apr. 15 (Box OR31)
      - 071/AV/917: Journalist Hyacinthe Bicamumpaka, 1994 Apr. 16 (Box OR31)
      - 072A/AV/918: Journalists Jean Francois Nsengiyuma and Gilles Nizeyimana, 1994 Apr. 17, news bulletins, interview with Froduald Karamira of Mouvement démocratique républicain (MDR), Major General Bizimana's speech, and update on war, 1994 Apr. 17 (Box OR31)
      - 072B/AV/918: Journalists Jean Francois Nsengiyuma and Jules-Maurice Kagina, news bulletin, update on Rwandan Patriotic Front (RPF) and Forces armees rwandaises (FAR) movements, President Sindikubwabo's speech, United Nations Assistance Mission for Rwanda (UNAMIR) negotiations and departure of Belgians, Simbizi of Coalition for the Defense of the Republic (CDR) on Belgians, 1994 Apr. 17 (Box OR31)
      - 074A/AV920: Journalist Agenesta Mukarutama, 1994 Apr. 17 (Box OR31)
      - 074B/A/V 920: Journalist Agenesta Mukarutama, 1994 Apr. 17 (Box OR31)
      - 075A/AV/922: Journalist Jean Baptist Bamwanga, interview of minister on massacres, statement from Ministry of Defense, atrocities of Rwandan Patriotic Front (RPF), statement of Gaudence Nyirahabimana, interview of Sixbert Ndayambaje regarding RPF infrastructure, 1994 Apr. 18 (Box OR31)
      - 075B/AV/922: unidentified journalists, conclusion of interview with Sixbert Ndayambaje regarding RPF's plans and network, news bulletins and letter from "Association of those who love Rwanda," statement from "Intikiza," 1994 Apr. 18 (Box OR31)
        Continued from 075A.
      - 080A/AV/928: Journalist Jean Baptiste Bamwanga, 1994 Apr. 21 (Box OR31)
      - 080B/AV/928: Journalist Jean Baptiste Bamwanga regarding RPF power, 1994 Apr. 21 (Box OR31)
      - 099A/RTLM: Journalists Gaspard Gahigie and Kantano Habimana, regarding governments response to situation in Ruhengeri and complicity with Inkotanyi, 1993 Nov. 20 (Box OR31)
      - 099A: Journalist Kantano Habimana regarding criticism of political opponent, criticism of RPF/RPA, revision 2003 Nov. 4 (Box OR31)
        Complete transcript.
      - 099B/RTLM: Journalists Gaspard Gahigie and Kantano Habimana, 1992 Nov. 20 (Box OR31)
      - 108/Radio Muhabura: unnamed journalist, 1994 June 6 (Box OR31)
      - 115/RTLM: Journalists Valerie Bemeriki, Kantano Habimana, et al., 1994 Apr. 22 (Box OR31)
      - 131A/RTLM 18: Journalists Kantano Habimana, Ananie Nkurunziza, et al., 1994 May 23 (Box OR31)
      - 131B/RTLM 18: Journalists Kantano Habimana and Ananie Nkurunziza, 1994 May 23 (Box OR31)
      - 134A/RTLM: Journalist Valerie Bemeriki, 1994 June 4 (Box OR31)
      - 134B/RTLM: Journalists Kantano Habimana, Georges Ruggiu and Bernard Mukingo, 1994 June 5 (Box OR32)
      - 137A/RTLM: Journalists Gaspard Gahigie, Valerie Bemeriki, Kantano Habimana and Georges Ruggiu, 1994 June 28 (Box OR32)
      - 139A/C.2/K 95 RTLM: Journalists Kantano Habimana et al., 1993 Nov. 24 (Box OR32)
    - The Rwanda Archive: Audio, video and print database, 1997 (Box OR32)
    - Rwanda interviews - Devil's Children, undated (Box OR32)
    - Rwanda transcripts
      - Tape 1, Moeneback, Hélène translator, 1994 May 14 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 12.
      - Tape 2, Nsengiyumva, Fabien, translator, 1995 May 16-17 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Oct.
      - Tape 4, Nsengiyumva, Fabien, translator, 1994 Dec. 4 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 17.
      - Tape 7, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 May 16 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 19.
      - Tape 8, Gatabazi, Jean Marie translator, 1994 Apr. 22 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1996 Sep. 16.
      - Tape 9, Moeneback, Hélène, translator, 1994 May 18 (Box OR32)
      - Tape 10, Eliphaz, Bimenyimana, translator, 1994 May 21 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1997 Jul. 23.
      - Tape 12, Ndimurkundo, Yves-Florent, translator, 1995 May 28 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 31.
      - Tape 14, Mpambara, Lydie, translator, 1994 May 29 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Sep. 6.
      - Tape 15, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 May 29 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Feb. 11.
      - Tape 16, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 May 30 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Mar. 11.
      - Tape 17, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 May 31 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Nov. 2.
      - Tape 18, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 May 31 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Nov. 9.
      - Tape 19, Moenback, Hélène, translator, 1994 Jan. 6 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Nov. 15.
      - Tape 20, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 Feb. 6 (Box OR32)
      - Tape 22, Ntigulirwa, Jean Marie Vianney, translator, 1994 Mar. 6 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1996 Mar. 25.
      - Tape 24, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 May 6 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1995 Nov. 29.
      - Tape 25, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 May 6 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1997 May 29.
      - Tape 28, Mujawingoma, Olive, translator, 1994 June 9 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1994 Jul. 9.
      - Tape 30, Moeneback, Hélène, translator, 1994 June 18 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1996 Feb. 1.
      - Tape 31, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 June 19 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1997 May 7.
      - Tape 33, Moeneback, Hélène, translator, 1994 June 20 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1996 Feb. 16.
      - Tape 35, Mpambara, Lydie Rose Marie, translator, 1994 June 20 (Box OR32)
        Translation date 1997 July 3.
      - Tape 36, unidentified translator, 1994 June 21 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Jul. 9.
      - Tape 37, Mpambara, Lydie, translator, 1994 June 22 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 May 21.
      - Tape 39, Habiyambere, Antoine, translator, 1994 Jul. 1 (Box OR33)
        Translation date, 1995 Oct. 23.
      - Tape 40, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 Jul. 2 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 24.
      - Tape 41, Moeneback, Hélène, translator, 1994 Jul. 3 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1995 Oct. 30.
      - Tape 42, Nsengiyumva, Fabien, translator, 1994 Jul. 3 (Box OR33)
      - Tape 43, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 Jul. 3 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1996 Oct. 21.
      - Tape 45, Mukakigeli, Gaudence, translator, 1994 Jan. 6 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 June 9.
      - Tape 49, Mukakigeli, Gaudence, translator, undated (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Aug. 5.
      - Tape 50, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, undated (Box OR33)
        Translation date, 1997 Apr. 28.
      - Tape 51, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, undated (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Aug. 25.
      - Tape 52, Mukakigeli, Gaudence, translator, undated (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Jul. 25.
      - Tape 53, Ndimurkundo, Yves-Florent, translator, undated (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1995 Jul. 28.
      - Tape 57, Ndimurkundo, Yves-Florent, translator, 1994 Apr. 7 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1996 Jul. 24.
      - Tape 58, Mujawingoma, Olive, translator, 1994 Apr. 9 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1994 Jul. 31.
      - Tape 59, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 Apr. 10 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1996 June 25.
      - Tape 62, Zikuliza, Charles, translator, 1994 Apr. 11 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1995 Sep. 3.
      - Tape 64, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 Apr. 13 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1997 Apr. 15.
      - Tape 65, Mpambara, Lydie, translator, 1994 Apr. 14 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1996 Jul. 11.
      - Tape 133, Furufuru, Léopold, translator, 1994 May 24 (Box OR33)
        Translation date 1996 Jan. 2.